Agent experience is a discipline, not a
specific tool. If you're thinking about,
okay, I have to support agents, so I
just need an MCP server. That's thinking
far too narrowly about this problem.
These are all solutions that are kind of
under the umbrella of an agent
experience. But the other reality is we
have a lot of ideas about what works
today and then we're going to prove
those wrong [music] tomorrow and then
we're going to keep iterating on it. But
we're right in the middle of it. And so
where should you actually start? So this
is going to be my recommendation.
>> [music]
>> So, the first thing like if if your team
is just a bunch of one person bands um
or not doing any of this at all, start
with figuring that out, right? Like I
think that there's a hunch. Yeah, my
team's using AI, whatever. Like like we
we're AI native. It's like no, like like
figure out what they're using. Ask them
figure out what's working, what's not.
And and this doesn't have to be a big
effort. Get a Google form, whatever,
vibe code it, and just ask them what
what agents are they using? What's
working well? And to be clear, don't ask
them the question that we asked them a
year ago, two years ago. We're like,
"Have you tried any agents?" It's like,
no. Like, everyone's probably tried an
AI tool, but what we want to know is
what people are using every day or every
other day. what's working, what's not.
And it's important to understand that
for for many reasons, but not least of
which is the fact that there are lots of
AI agents and tools and combinations of
them. And then all the work that you're
going to be doing to um improve the
agent experience. This helps scope it
much better. Just understand what people
are doing. If they're using spec driven
development, that might be a little
different looking of an agent experience
than if they're using some some other
tool or they're really into stuff like
lovable or bolt new things like that.
So audit audit what people are doing.
Figure out what's going on. Um and then
start to build your internal community,
right? all that really, you know, has to
all that is really involved in doing
that is getting them together every, you
know, infrequently, but get them
together to talk about the issues that
they're running into. Talk about the
tools that they're using. Um, if you
really want to learn something cool,
come up with a problem or take something
some take some ticket off the board and
say, "Hey, I'm going to solve this
together and I'm going to watch you
solve it your way. I'm going to solve it
my way and we're going to we're going to
learn together." And that's some version
of of pair programming here uh where
there's also an AI agent involved and
that is so illuminating in terms of like
how what people understand differently
about the different the code base how
they approach the problem and and it
will also start to build up your
internal community um to to build
towards an agent experience.
So taking the next step forward, right?
Uh you know the agents that you need to
support
now you need to help them be better. Guy
did an a fantastic job of explaining
this for me earlier with with with some
data around backing up that uh the LMS
themselves are not sufficient in terms
of understanding your codebase. Um and
and the reality is is if there is a gap
in knowledge, it will confidently make
things up or decide for you. It's not
always made up false. It just might just
be totally different. Like his example
of picking a theme that was not the
right theme [snorts] um to combat this,
right? Context files are where you need
to spend your initial time, right? Um
either you know depending on the tools,
right? agents files, steering files,
cloud code uh cloud files, cloudMD
files. Um these are going to be very
important um nuggets of information. And
you know some rules of thumb that I
think about is if uh
if you could if you couldn't simplify
something, make it obvious, right? So
many code bases you see like, okay, to
run a test suite, it's this some magical
command that you got to run. That's not
obvious. If if you have those, make sure
that they're in your context. Um
other areas are like if you have a
decoupled architecture, so you have a
front end um that's decoupled from your
backend which might be decoupled from
your your data layer etc. It doesn't
necessarily know those connections and
you need to make those clear or it will
make those connections it it'll make
them up [laughter]
every time. Um [snorts] and that's going
to be incredibly important. Um and and
and especially whenever you get into
this world of as people are
um iterating on this and they start
finding that
hey it's it something that we thought
was obvious wasn't it's going to keep
making those things up and adding those
into your um uh agents files and and
steering files is going to be incredibly
important.
The next thing I mentioned um is is the
core dependency uh documentation. I'd
mentioned the core dependency of the the
front end has a dependency on this back
end. It's over here. Here's how you use
it. Here's how you find information
about it. And that's incredibly
important. But there's also this this
problem of um dependency uh
documentation in like third party
modules, things like that, even first
party separated modules. And and and Guy
went in uh a lot of detail about that.
This has been bothering me for so long.
Um because you know the reality is
especially with you know brownfield type
of projects is
I I have developers or so the model is
trained on version one of my API the
latest version is version three but all
my developers using version two and so
like it messes it up nine times out of
10 um and and the the tooling for
getting this right isn't great today. I
was actually, you know, writing this, I
was very stoked to see Tesla's, you
know, registry and things like that that
they're doing. Um, and so I'm going to
explore that more. I think that's very
exciting. I definitely agree that
there's actually, um, more onus needs to
be put on the open source community to
deliver these things. The way I kind of
see the Tesla registry is like, well, if
every uh, dependency had to have its
types hosted somewhere else, right? like
really the types, the documentation for
it really needs to be there. But we also
have the second problem where especially
open source repos
there's people who build on them and
then there's people who use them and
those are different documentation and so
like even it still gets a little bit
harder and harder the the more you try
to optimize but again we're all figuring
this out together so that's fine. Um if
if you use context 7 that's also
something that uh people people use. Uh,
I've I've run into issues with it not
doing very well on the versioning side
of things. Um, but regardless, if you
have a key dependency that's a third
party module,
make sure it's in your context. Make
sure you're using it right, especially
if it's things like data based
databased um uh because there's it's
just a such a dense topic and tool set
that um it ends up getting pretty
confused with those types of tools. So
make it clear and especially for very
large code bases um the concept of
knowledge graphs um there's many
different implementations of them
cognition released uh deep wiki and and
code maps recently but it's this you
know the reality is is if you have a
really large codebase and you're asking
it to do things every time that you try
to ask it to do something it's got to
kind of figure it out on its own and the
larger the codebase the longer that
takes the more expensive it is the more
likely is it's going miss parts or get
confused.
And this is where knowledge graphs
really come in where you can kind of
pre-roduce
this kind of understanding of the
overall architecture, how things relate
to one another and summarize those. And
so before it tries to do things, it
consults there first. And those are very
helpful for larger code bases. [snorts]
Uh feedback loops are going to be
incredibly important. Um, so if you're
if you're already getting your internal
community together, working with them to
say, "Look, whenever we're having an
issue, if a if a human had to manually
intervene in an agent uh agent's
workflow, get that documented. Get that
into context. Um, if you're talking to
that senior engineer who's been there
for 15 years and has all the tribal
knowledge in their head, if you every
time you have to consult them, if that
doesn't go back in documentation or
context, I don't know what you're
doing." But like that that's this
internal feedback loop. You have to have
some forcing functions to make sure that
your agents understand because unlike
you, they they can't go ask uh
necessarily that that uh that tenure
developer who has all the information in
their head. So establish feedback loops
with your internal team. One practice
that I really enjoy doing is I have this
MC MCP where it's like, okay, if the
agent's really going off the rails here,
um, I have it look back and say, what
could we have done better here? It's
like an agent therapy session. Like,
what what should we do better to make
sure that you're going to get this right
next time? And specifically update the
context files to make sure that happens.
And then especially like once we do that
um assuming it makes sense at the time
having it try again and then go from
there. I have a lot of good results with
that as well. [snorts]
I'm sure most of you if not all of you
are using AI review tools in in your um
uh code bases and your CI pipelines and
such. the so I won't go too deep into
that but like the one thing that I think
is an addition on top of that is not
only having your your
uh AI review tool figure out what's
wrong with a thing but also suggests
when there are patterns that were
missing from your context files that
would have prevented this from happening
in the future. So like this is you're
getting towards a step of trying to
automate some of this feedback loop.